Guide to the Carolee Schneemann Papers M1892
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series 11. Other artists
  The following unordered list of people and groups lends some sense of her milieu: Stan Brakhage, Clayton Eshleman, Robert Kelly, George Quasha, Mike Bidlo, Christo & Jeanne-Claude, Jerome Rothenberg, Bruce Andrews, Joseph Cornell, Peter Garland/Soundings Press, Malcolm Goldstein, Philip Corner, Kathy Acker, Eleanor Antin, Mary Beth Edelson, Robert Haller, Claes Oldenberg, Charles Henri Ford, Peter Moore, Yoko Ono, Lil Picard, John Duncan, Nigel Rolfe, Anne Waldman, Christian Marclay, Barbara Ess, Linda Montano, Susan Sontag, Robert Rauschenberg, Ray Johnson, Opal Louis-Nations, Robert Filliou, Annie Sprinkle, Jill Johnston, Marina Abramović, Valie Export, Derek Jarman (inscribed book), Andy Warhol (poss. inscribed book), Charles Olson, Kwiek-Kulik, Julian Beck & Judith Malina/Living Theater, Judy Malloy, Centro De Arte Y Communication, Bob & Bob, David Det Hompson, Wendy Geller, Rose Garrard, John Giorno, Michael McClure, Kurt Schwitters, Marcia Resnick, Berty Skuber, Val Telberg (incl. inscribed copy of Anais Nin’s House in Incest for which he took photos), Wolf Vostell, Charles Stein, Jonas Mekas/Anthology Film Archives, Poetry Project, Film-Maker’s Cooperative, The Kitchen, Franklin Furnace, Canyon Cinema, Idiolects, Language, Letters, Left Curve, La Mamelle, Caterpillar, New Observations, New Wilderness Letter, Performance, Temblor, Wallpaper, Working Papers, Something Else Press/Black Bear, Treacle, McPherson & Co.
  - A (Box 95, Folder 6)
  - Kathy Acker/Black Tarantula books (Box 180)
  - A-B books & magazines (Box 180)
  - B-C books & magazines (Box 181)
  - B (Box 96, Folder 5)
  - Mike Bidlo (Box 96, Folder 1-2)
  - Stan Brakhage (Box 96, Folder 3-4)
  - C (Box 97, Folder 2)
  - Christo & Jeanne-Claude (Box 97, Folder 1)
  - Caterpillar magazine [includes issues with CS] (Box 181)
  - D (Box 97, Folder 4)
  - D-F books & magazines (Box 182)
  - E (Box 98, Folder 1)
  - Clayton Eshleman correspondence ["duplicates", some photocopied"], 1960s (Box 112, Folder 1)
  - Clayton Eshleman correspondence, 1970-1974 (Box 112, Folder 2)
  - Clayton Eshleman books (Box 182)
  - Clayton Eshleman correspondence, 1975-1979, 1985-1988, 1994 (Box 112, Folder 3)
  - F (Box 98, Folder 2)
  - Fluxus general (Box 94, Folder 3)
  - Fluxus artist correspondence (Box 94, Folder 4)
    Includes correspondence (most relatively brief) with Al & Bibbe Hansen, Geoff Hendricks, Jon Hendricks, Alison Knowles, Charlotte Moorman, and a few others.
  - Fluxus/happening/Judson books & magazines (Box 190, Folder 1-8)
    Includes books and other material by Allan Kaprow, Dick Higgins, Alison Knowles, Jackson Mac Low, Nam June Paik and others
  - G (Box 98, Folder 4)
  - G-J books & magazines (Box 183)
  - Peter Garland (Box 98, Folder 3)
  - Peter Garland/Soundings books (Box 183)
  - H (Box 98, Folder 5)
  - Dick Higgins (Box 94, Folder 5)
  - J (Box 98, Folder 6)
  - Judson/dance/etc. (Box 95, Folder 1)
    Includes programs, fliers, articles, and other material related to Judson Dance Theater, Yvonne Rainer, Peter Moore, The Bridge, Surplus Dance Theater, Pocket Theater, Kinetic Theater, etc.
  - K (Box 98, Folder 7)
  - K-L books & magazines (Box 184)
  - Naomi Levinson writing etc. (Box 109, Folder 8)
  - P books & magazines (Box 186)
  - R (Box 101, Folder 3)
  - Robert Kelly books (Box 184)
  - L (Box 99, Folder 1)
  - M (Box 100, Folder 3)
  - M-O books & magazines (Box 185)
  - Manipulations - A Judson Publication, 1967-10 (Box 95, Folder 2)
    Two copies with slight variations of this artist book/magazine production. another copy has been filed with other writing by Schneemann (in the Publicity/printed material series).
  - Sands Murray-Wassink (Box 99, Folder 2-4)
  - Sands Murray-Wassink (Box 100, Folder 1-2)
  - N (Box 100, Folder 4)
  - O (Box 101, Folder 1)
  - P (Box 101, Folder 2)
  - George Quasha books (Box 186)
  - R-S books & magazines (Box 187)
  - Jerome Rothenberg books (Box 186)
  - S (Box 101, Folder 4-5)
  - S-V books & magazines (Box 188)
  - T (Box 102, Folder 1)
  - James Tenney (Box 95, Folder 3-4)
    First husband, composer, musician, together for over ten years. Includes correspondence (also with his last wife Lauren Pratt), programs, articles, etc. There are also a few pages from a diary. More material on Tenney is present elsewhere in collection.
  - Tone Roads Ensemble/new music (Box 95, Folder 5)
    Primarily early 1960s fliers for concerts by the Tone Roads Ensemble (many designed & printed by Schneemann), as well as correspondence with Malcolm Goldstein and a few items related to Philip Corner, John Cage, David Tudor, Tony Conrad, LaMonte Young, and others. Musicians and composers are also filed elsewhere in this series.
  - V-W (Box 102, Folder 2)
  - W-Z books & magazines (Box 189)
  - misc.unidentified art, art-related clippings, gallery postcards, other ephemera (Box 102, Folder 3)
  - group shows & collaborations (Box 102, Folder 4-5)
  - group shows & collaborations (Box 103, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous artists books - unsigned, conceptual, miniature, etc. (Box 189)
  - cassette, CD (Box 189)
  - water-damaged magazines & catalogs (Box 189)
- Series 12. Photographs, slides, negatives
  - Subseries 12.1. Production Files
    Contains photographs (both prints and photocopies) and textual material, presumably gathered for various projects.
    - Derow (Box 120, Folder 1)
    - color copies of photographs - cats, house, CS, Tenney (Box 120, Folder 2-3)
    - Vespers Pool (Box 120, Folder 4)
    - Text Infinity Kisses (Box 120, Folder 5)
    - SNAFU (Box 120, Folder 6)
    - Portrait Partials (Box 120, Folder 7)
    - Alison White (Box 120, Folder 8)
    - Scanned Hi-Res Images on File (Box 120, Folder 9)
    - Projections (Box 120, Folder 10)
    - Vespers Pool (Box 121, Folder 1)
    - ArtPace (Box 121, Folder 2)
    - Work [images] (Box 121, Folder 3)
    - Photos of CS (Box 121, Folder 4)
    - Photos of CS, others, 1980s-1990s (Box 121, Folder 5)
    - Vespers Pool (Box 121, Folder 6)
    - Nostalgia - Past to Present (Box 121, Folder 7)
    - Works, 1960s (Box 121, Folder 8)
    - Works, 1970s (Box 121, Folder 9)
    - Up To & Including Her Limits - New Museum (Box 121, Folder 10)
    - War Mop Pix (Box 121, Folder 11)
    - Performance, 1960s (Box 121, Folder 12)
    - Performance, 1970s (Box 122, Folder 1)
    - Performance, 1980s (Box 122, Folder 2)
    - Performance, 1990s (Box 122, Folder 3)
    - Polarity Burn (Box 122, Folder 4)
    - Mortal Coils, NYC, 1994 (Box 122, Folder 5)
    - Photos of Work (Box 122, Folder 6)
    - Saw Over Want (Box 122, Folder 7)
    - Hand/Heart (Box 122, Folder 8)
    - Infinity Kisses Xerox & Photo (Box 122, Folder 9)
    - Works, 1980s-1990s (Box 122, Folder 10)
    - Family [incl. Eve Bailey Lerner, CS' godmother] (Box 122, Folder 11)
    - I Ching Apple Pie Photos (Box 122, Folder 12)
    - Book Objects [photos] (Box 122, Folder 13)
    - Works [notebook], 1987 (Box 122, Folder 14)
    - CineProbe MOMA, 1992 (Box 122, Folder 15)
    - Cluny - Lights (Box 122, Folder 16)
    - Friends (Box 122, Folder 17)
    - Kitch's Last Meal (Box 122, Folder 18)
    - Emily Harvey (Box 123, Folder 1)
    - David Levi Strauss [writing] (Box 123, Folder 2)
    - Fluxus Deluxe (Box 123, Folder 3)
    - Photos, 2003 (Box 123, Folder 4)
    - Photos, 2002 (Box 123, Folder 5)
    - Kathy Brew (Box 123, Folder 6)
    - Misc. Xerox (Box 123, Folder 7)
    - Dada (Box 123, Folder 8)
    - Photos, CS etc. [prints & photocopies], 1960s (Box 123, Folder 9)
    - Rauschenberg Memorial (Box 123, Folder 10)
    - CS photos (Box 123, Folder 11)
    - NYC (Box 123, Folder 12)
    - Photos, 1970s (Box 123, Folder 13)
    - Photos, 1980s (Box 123, Folder 14)
    - Photos, 2000 (Box 123, Folder 15)
  - Subseries 12.2. Slides (boxes numbered 1-8)
    - 1A (Box 145)
      Including Dirty Pictures, Paintings on Paper, and Blood Diary.
    - 2A (Box 145)
      Includes Eye Body, Interior Scroll, Up To and Including Her Limits, Forbidden Actions, Cornell, and Eros, Parts of a Body House, Saw Over Want, among others.
    - 3A (Box 146)
      Includes War Mop, Vulva's Morphia, Cycladic Imprints, Infinity Kisses and Dustworks, among others.
    - 4A (Box 146)
      Includes Unexpectedly Research, Cycladic Imprints, and others.
    - 5A (Box 147)
      Early Paintings/Painting Constructions
    - 6A (Box 147)
      Assorted slides from various exhibitions including Snows, Cooking with Apes, and Lateral Splay, among others.
    - 7A (Box 148)
      Includes Meat Joy, Water Light/Water Needle, Vespers Pool among others.
    - 8A (Box 148)
      Includes ABC, Vulva, Mystic Duplicates, and Art is Reactionary, among others.
  - Subseries 12.3. Slides (boxes numbered 7-23)
    Each case contains approximately 400 slides.
    - Travels & Friends [7], 1992-1995 (Box 149)
    - Travel-Friends ‘98/Vienna/MOCA ‘99/Rothenberg/CalArts/Ohio/Schliffer/Minos/Brakhage/2004 [10], 1998-2004 (Box 149)
    - Home/Friends/LA/Montreal [11], 1998-2004 (Box 150)
    - Travel 93,94,95/Friends 1994/California/Landscape/Family [13], 1993-1995 (Box 150)
    - J&C, cats 1990s/Psyche/Furrow/Lantern [15], 1988-1993 (Box 151)
      Slides of various exhibitions including Psyche, Furrow and Lantern.
    - Travels 1981-92: Holland/DC/Ohio/England/Colorado/Arizona/Chicago ‘92/Deer Ice ‘87/NY Fire ‘87/Mother/Sante Fe/Tom Maura B. (Bar Tur Games)/Cactus [16], 1981-1997 (Box 151)
    - Cluny & pets/home base 1976-1987/Wicca/Lumiere/Lantern [19] (Box 152)
    - Teaching Slides: Kent State/UCLA/Tahoe/UMass/Pratt ‘94/Lecture Boston/Table/Austin [18], 1977-1994 (Box 152)
    - Travels & Friends/Telluride/Nitsch/Europe 1978 [20], 1973-1980 (Box 153)
    - Travel-Cats-Home 2000 [23] (Box 153)
  - Subseries 12.4. Photographs & slides (M and A numbered group)
    - Bad Negs [M1] (Box 26, Folder 6)
      Approximately 20 pages of bad negatives and contact sheets.
    - 1990s prints, negatives & diskettes [M3], 1980s-2002 (Box 154)
      Computer diskettes [8] are dated 7/31/98 & 1/8/99. L.A. with Treasure '99; 1980s Bruce Cluny Lantern; Psyche Furrow 90s; Fugs & LA 99; Home-Annex-House-Snow 97-01; Roger Conover Neumann CS 95; Nevada - Sculpture Class '94; Home 90s CS & Cats; Landscape Spring 95; C & Works '95; 90s Home Freind Parties; Friends 91-97; Beatty Birthday 80s Dietz Shit; Loft Party 10/02.
    - Vesper prints, negatives & diskettes [M4], 2000-2002 (Box 155)
      Vesper; PPOW 3/02 & Book Party 02; Parties Winter Fall 02 NY & Fla.; Jan & Alan & Cats 02; Bday Loft 02; Mass MOCA Jon Hendricks 01; Schnetter Performs 02; Istanbul 01; Winter Snow Home 00; No.2 11/2000; White Box 3/01; Party Loft 00; Maine 01; Brew. Loft Home 3/02; Parties - Jan & Alan; Quasha Parties 01
    - prints, negatives [M5], 2002-2004 (Box 156)
      Montreal 2004; Vienna 2004 Museum; Aug. 04 Minos Pam Lee; Family; Atlantic Center 04; Fall 03 Beautiful Super Imposure [?]; Karma Dead; Dec.03 Brente Party; Roof-Joyce-Cats 03; Out of ACtions - LA Vienna; No.03 Montreal; Malcolm Gilles; Fall 03 Davis Calif. & Cats Lama; June 03 LA Mathis & P. Hiller; Photo Espana 7/02; Minneapolis 02; Venus Vectors 02; Minnesota 7/02
    - Family Friends [M8] (Box 27, Folder 1-2)
      Approximately 150 slides of Schneemann's personal life.
    - Friends, Travel, Home [M9], 1970-1999 (Box 27, Folder 3-4)
      Approximately 400 photographs of travel abroad. Also includes approximately 35 slides.
    - photographs [prints, negatives, mounted] (Flat-box 127, Folder 1-4)
      Includes photo documentation of American I-Ching Apple Pie performance 1975
    - Friends, Travel, Home [M10], 1990-1999 (Box 27, Folder 5-6)
      Approximately 300 photographs various content. Also includes approximately 35 slides and 25 negative strips.
    - photographs [A4] (Box 134, Folder 3)
      about 34 large black and white photographs of various sizes of landscapes, nudes, parties and happenings, as well as Schneemann's own sketches and black and white photographs of cats. Some photographs by Sobelewski, Gene Hines, Bill Thompson, etc.
  - Subseries 12.5. Other photographs
    - Illinois Central mounted photographs, Max Waldman, 1968 (Box 127, Folder 5)
    - photographs of CS and others (Box 112, Folder 4)
      Contains copies and original prints. Many depict performances and workspace. Includes Schneemann's 1960 university ID card.
- Series 13. Media
  Recordings of and for art and projects; lectures and workshops; actuality/field recordings (some of which were used in her art); answering machine cassettes, etc. Works from others are also present, including several films from Stan Brakhage given to Schneemann and James Tenney. A searchable spreadsheet indexing all of the collection's media (based on their labels) is available here: http://purl.stanford.edu/sn229md3325 Please note that none of this material has been digitally transferred as of 4/2016.
  - Subseries 13.1. Audio
    - audiocassettes (Boxes 211-226)
      Most are recordings of or from various projects; Schneemann also maintained a collection of answering machine cassettes and environmental recordings (conversations, cats, trains, etc.).
    - open reel tapes (Boxes 227-230, Boxes 231-233, 240)
  - Subseries 13.2. Moving Image
    - videocassettes (Boxes 191-205, Boxes 206-209)
      Mostly VHS, some Beta and a few U-Matic.
    - optical media (Box 210)
    - film (Boxes 235-238, Boxes 241-243, Box 239)
- Series 14. Costumes/environments
  - Rauschenberg E.A.T. dress (Box 144)
  - Chromelodeon - Lucinda's Costume, 1963 (Box 173)
    "Chromelodeon". Kinetic Theater with dancers, actors. Judson Dance Theater, NYC.
  - 3 Queen's Dog Costumes - Tops and Matching Bottoms, 1965 (Box 174)
    The Queen's Dog". Kinetic Theater. Judson Dance Theater, NYC.
  - Chromelodeon [two pink boas], 1963 (Box 175)
  - Chromelodeon Environment Piece with Meat Joy Costume [bikini] Sewn On. A Later Meat Joy Creation?, 1963 (Box 176)
  - Chromelodeon Environment, 1963 (Box 177)
  - Chromelodeon - Deborah Hay's Costume, 1963 (Box 178)
  - Chromelodeon - Bones & Fur Dress, 1963 (Box 179)
- Series 15. Awards & recognition, bios, portfolios
  - Early Kinetic Theater Chronology [portfolio with original layout], 1968 (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Bios/portfolios/itineraries,etc. (Box 124, Folder 4)
  - American Academy of Arts & Letters, 2002 (Box 124, Folder 6)
  - awards, certificates, etc. (Box 125, Folder 1)
- Series 15. Miscellaneous
  - ephemera (Box 112, Folder 5)
  - postcards, blank, unsent but annotated, etc. (Box 112, Folder 6, Box 29, Folder 4)
  - box of rubber stamps for projects, addresses, etc. (Box 51, Object 9)
  - wooden box with splicers, other film editing tools (Box 234)